this is software engineering radio the
podcast for professional developers on
the web at SC - radio dotnet SC radio is
brought to you by the I Triple E
Computer Society I Triple E software
magazine online at computer org slash
software
welcome everyone to software engineering
radio today I'll be your host my name is
Kim Carter and today we have a Zane
lakeya's gist on the show Zane Leckie is
the founder and chief security officer
signal sciences he serves on the
advisory boards of the internet bug
bounty program in the US State
Department Becht open technology fund
Zane was previously director of security
engineering at Etsy and a senior
security consultant at AIESEC partners
Zane has been featured in many notable
media outlets is a frequent speaker at
top industry conferences and is a
contributing author for our mobile
application and security
hacking exposed we 2.0 and hacking voice
over IP now welcome to today's show Zane
hey Kim thanks for having me on I really
really appreciate it looking forward to
the conversation today we're going to be
discussing application security inherit
applies to software engineers what are
the assets an attacker may target what
are the risks to those assets and the
types of countermeasures we need to be
thinking about in order to mitigate the
risks there's some relevant articles
from the I Triple E Computer Society on
today's topic but we replication
security threats countermeasures and
pitfalls and that can be found at
computer org slash CES DL we had a show
on docker security with a Diego moniker
that was shown number 290 and we've also
looked at bringing the security focus up
front with a show on DVI cops with
Frances Reynard that was show number 288
and the discussions are Zain in myself
head are leading up to today's show we
discussed here how many types of
security being pushed toward the
application layer with that software
engineering Radiohead a show called web
app security in 2009 with Bruce seems
that was show number 128 and I had her
une mère I reason
on the show discussing network security
in its show number three zero two and
leading up to today's show Ozona myself
discussed where we think are the lowest
hanging fruit is in terms of exploiting
organizations via information security
defects today's show really leads on
from the last show I recorded with her
own Mia are we on network security we're
just going to start with some basic
questions to start with what are the
most effective attack techniques for the
most common vulnerabilities today yeah
so I think the the way in which you've
kind of attacked organizations has
really changed over time here and that's
why that's why I think it's kind of
exciting to both talk about the web
application side of things as we are
going to today as well as the
conversation you got to have with Haroon
of kind of the changing nature of
attacking endpoints and things on that
side of things um so I mean if you look
at how attackers have really targeted
organizations historically I mean we're
talking you know 10 15 20 years ago you
really attacked the the infrastructure
right you go and map a given
organization's IP range you'd find
something there and and you'd you'd go
really attack that at the infrastructure
layer and you if you look at how because
of the kind of changing infrastructure
topologies and everything like that you
look at how most attackers target
organizations today and it's really
shifted either up to the application
layer or drifted out to the endpoint
side of things and so I think the the
balance of those two and really the the
conversation you got to have with rune
and the the focus today on the web
application side of things I think from
a defensive perspective that's really
where so many of us are thinking about
how do we adapt our security programs to
really cover where the attackers have
gone to so I think you know for the
application layer in particular you know
it's not it didn't shift there because
attackers woke up one day and suddenly
wanted to start attacking applications
or anything like that you look at you
know how do organizations actually store
data and interact with that data and
that's really the data that the
attackers are after in the first place
and you look at how it used to be a
variety of kind of custom ways in which
organizations would interact with the
data that they have and now you
flash-forward to today
often it's done via web applications
right it might be done via standard and
a browser web application or done via a
mobile application that's backed by some
sort of web service or something like
that and an api there but so much of how
we create and store and access data as
organization today is really done via
the web layer in terms of application
security is software engineers what our
biggest concerns and how do we fix these
yeah so our our concerns are many and
how we fix them is is can be complicated
you know I think the the big thing that
shifted on the concern the side of
things is really that you know in the
past when people have talked about web
application security issues they really
meant kind of a wasp injection sort of
issues right sequel injection and XSS
and and things like that and don't get
me wrong those are absolutely important
but what's so funny is when you talk
with development teams or devops teams
or security folks dealing with web
applications or AP is so much of what
actually keeps them up at night is
attacks on the business logic its
application misuse its account takeovers
against your customers it's application
level D doses and things like that and
so I think from the you know what's kind
of change from the threat side of things
it's that there's just kind of a broader
attack surface there and it's no longer
just the classic input validation
injection issues that that we've known
over the past and then how do we start
to address those I think the biggest
thing and we can really you know jump
down a few levels here over the course
of the show but I'd say from you know a
starting the top view point it's really
that security tools and techniques can't
only be consumed by security people
anymore that this shift to DevOps is
shift a cloud the fact that applications
are being created and delivered so much
faster and so much faster now it really
means that for security tooling the
development teams and the DevOps teams
need to be able to be kind of
self-sufficient with security whether
that's getting visibility into where and
how they're being attacked or having you
know different static analysis tools or
different security tools that they can
consume themselves but I think the big
shift for us as security professionals
is we
used to really have security tools that
were only directly consumable by the
security team and I think that's really
shifted to how do we empower the
development teams and DevOps teams with
security tools that they can consume
directly it's a familiar topic shifting
security lifts or shifting it into the
development teams something that
engineers have really got to come to
grips with I think that from you know
that perspective I think there's a lot
of reasons pushing on that right I think
that the the shift to DevOps in cloud
and moving things faster is one pressure
the other pressure that we're all
feeling from the security side is that
nobody can hire right there's a million
open headcount compared to how many
people there actually are to fill those
roles and so the only way security keeps
up is exactly as you just said it's
really that kind of shift left to get
security into the hands of the
developers and the DevOps teams
yeah Tech is gaining access to our
organization's assets and in what we
need to do as software engineers in
order to mitigate this yeah I think you
know a lot of this from my kind of
experiences going through this shift to
DevOps and cloud and everything there
was really about how can we give our
development teams in our DevOps teams
visibility into how their applications
are actually being used and attacked and
as you know those teams as you're saying
as they're kind of you know getting more
assets and everything like that more of
that data is shifting up to the
application level from a security
perspective what I've really seen be
successful both in my my own past and
with the organizations I talk to you
today is really about giving them that
visibility so they can say oh this API
that we put out there that we thought
nobody was using actually there's a
partner that's completely abusing it or
these micro services that we were
planning to be launching how do we
actually know when someone is attacking
them or anything like that and so
getting them that that level visibility
so at the same time that they're
creating new assets and having new data
and everything that they're know
collecting from users or providing to
your customers or anything there that
they have the visibility from the
security side that goes along with that
so that they can really own the
self-sufficiency of defending those
services
that they're providing I think I'm on a
really important thing that I to undo is
is to get a a security champion into the
development team to help all the other
engineers basically I catch on to what
they need to do in order to move forward
in terms of security and in feek the
rest of the team yeah exactly
in you know the good usage of that term
yeah that's I think that's very much
what you see many organizations doing
which is you know embedding security
into those teams sometimes that's by
taking a developer that's already on the
team and training them in security
sometimes it's bringing a security
person from the security team to just
kind of godet it and be dedicated to
that particular development team and
work with them I've seen both ways be
successful but I think the overall theme
that we're all really going through is
that you know there's more assets at the
web layer now than there ever used to be
those applications are being written and
changed even you know orders of
magnitude faster than they used to be
and security isn't able to hire nearly
as fast as we need to be and so the only
way in which we actually scale as
defenders is by working with the
development groups and DevOps teams and
that's really why I say developer why I
say defenders is that not just security
people anymore it could just be that
engineer on the development team who's
been trained a little bit in security
and really helps that development groups
think about it from the beginning what I
hear quite frequently is as a
development team why do we even care
about security and are we now
responsible for the security of the
organization's we work for yeah you know
it's it's one of those where I certainly
heard a bit of those I would say in the
past you know a fairly long time ago of
the should we care about security or you
know we don't care about security or
some like that I really have not found
that that to be true over the last
several years that I think that really
folks are recognizing that security is a
subset of good software engineering just
like performance just like reliability
just like operability and so security
being a piece of that it means it's not
some isolated specialized sort of thing
it's part of good engineering and I
think what I think the engineering side
has really started to figure that out I
think security is just starting
to see that that shift is is starting to
take place and I think that challenge
for many organizations is that they have
software engineers or DevOps teams that
want to do things well from the security
side but the security tools have not
really been written to keep up right
they've only been usable by security
folks or you turn on kind of a legacy
approach to static analysis or something
it spits out 10,000 false positives and
if you're committing you know if you're
shipping the production once a week now
or once a day you can't possibly run
that as your security control there so
really adapting the technologies and
techniques to the fact that folks are
recognizing security is a piece of
quality engineering yeah it could be a
New Zealand specific ring did always
seem to come across quite a bit totally
no III think it's one of those it
changes over time right I think that uh
that as we're embracing DevOps and cloud
it kind of shifts the way we do software
development so yeah so I'm just going to
move into a section around our top
tweets what we see as being the top
threats in the industry at the moment if
you look at the likes of the OWASP top
team over the past 14 years the defects
that we continue to add to our
applications haven't changed that much
it seems isn't industry what does your
take on whether we're actually improving
if not why not
in the age-old question how do we fix
this sure so I think there's kind of a
are we improving
I'd say the the other side of the
question is really are we are we
changing and I would say there's every
I'd say you'd be hard-pressed to find an
organization that doesn't feel like
they're going through some pretty
radical changes in the way that they
create and deliver software I mean it
was super jarring for me in my career
because I went from consulting with
AIESEC partners where I my last project
was with a US healthcare company that
deployed once every 18 months and I went
in and started as the head of security
at Etsy and they deployed they sat me
down said we deployed a production 20
times a day figure out security so I
think for most organizations it is not
that abrupt of a shift but I think the
most interesting thing for me of talking
to different different folks whether
it's a CIO a CTO seaso a Development
League anything like that over the last
let's say five years is you saw a lot of
organizations that said oh this
shift to agile or the shift to DevOps or
the shift to cloud it's not for us like
we're that's only for hipster Internet
companies or something like that and
what's fascinating is you go back and
talk to those organizations a year later
or something and let's say you're
speaking with the seaso and I can't tell
you at this point how many times I've
now heard we just got a new CIO they've
mandated we be completely in the cloud
in 18 months and how do we adapt and so
I think kind of now going back to your
question around you know that loss top
10 and really just even broader what is
you know are things changing from the
security perspective I think they have
to change and they have to change right
now more than any other time because the
way that we create and deliver software
this kind of shift agile and DevOps and
everything has existentially changed the
environment that we're operating in or
if you looked at you know if you looked
at ten years of ten years ago versus
eight years ago 400 aasif injection
issues or something like that had they
changed that much well not really now we
were still dealing with the same kind of
style of applications and and still
feeling a lot of the same threats but
you flash-forward to organizations going
through this shift now and that's really
almost every organization and it really
changes the way that security has to
interact with them and then from a
threats perspective because kind of to
your previous question because those
teams really have so many more sensitive
assets now than they used to it means
that the the threats that we're facing
have actually really greatly expanded I
mean if you go back to no web
application security 15 years ago 20
years ago it was like oh well that was
the marketing site so who really cared
there wasn't really that many sensitive
assets we put it in a DMZ like it's just
not that big a deal and I think for for
plenty of us that kind of came up from a
network security background that's still
a little bit of the mentality that that
we tend to have just because it was
historically true but the reality is the
world has changed out from under us and
that the web layer is where so much of
that sensitive data now sits and this
shift of web applications and api's and
micro services and everything there
means there's a broader set of assets
and the the broader threat of theta of
threats that we actually face really now
goes along with it
the other thing is the marketing site
that know and thinks or cares about has
is more than likely going to be where
the attacker against a foothold
exactly yes thanks yeah I say it's all
of the above now right we have to worry
about really complex business logic
issues and application misuse on a bunch
of our core platforms at the same time
if we don't patch that marketing site
that everyone is has forgotten that that
can that can lead to issues as well just
on its own you know that box under
someone's disk with sequel Server 2000
or whatever
certainly in regards to a lack of input
validation filtering and saidit ization
XSS cross-site request forgery the
injection types such as SQL I know SQL
command injection XML xslt xpath expiry
all DEP injections are you still seeing
these as being high on the list of
things software engineers and need to
focus on so there's I'd say there's good
news and bad news there I'd say the good
news is that the the platforms like the
language platforms themselves are
getting better at having really safe
defaults and everything like that the
the bad news are just less the bad news
and more just kind of the challenge is
that if you talk to any sort of
organization and you ask them what is
your technology stack their answer is
yes because they have everything right
and they're constantly bringing new ones
in and everything like that so I think
the challenge from both a development
perspective and from a security
perspective because really the two are
merging is okay as we bring in these new
technologies do they give us the same
sort of controls or coverage that the
last technology that we were used to
working with did right if you have one
technology that parameter eise's queries
for sequel for you by default or does
output encoding for you for XSS by
default and you you weave in a bit of
new technology to your stack does it
give the same guarantees and so that's
what I think a lot of organizations are
struggling with and why from the outside
it feels like oh you know how can it be
2017 and sequel injection is still a
thing well the answer is because the
technologies that we are working with
have changed and they probably changed
four or five different times during the
last time you've talked to that
organization or anything there so I
think from the defensive perspective
it's really thinking about how do we
what guarantees do our different
forms give us but I can tell you from
from being in the trenches on that one
what I've really learned is how do we
kind of abstract the security up a layer
so that we can cover the different
technology platforms that our
organization provides but in a way where
the developers don't have to don't have
to think about that right if every time
developers writing code they're having
to think oh does this particular
framework handle XSS for me that's a
problem right and so we need to be
thinking about how do we cover those
sort of issues in a way where someone
doesn't have to be asking themselves
those questions every time they're
writing code what advice do you have for
software engineers to be to manage data
store compromised yeah I think you know
that all kind of weaves into this focus
on shifting to how do we get visibility
into what's actually happening in
production right I think so many over
the past 10 15 years so much of the SDLC
has really focused on let's try to
eliminate all the bugs from code before
it goes to production and that's not
wrong you absolutely want to eliminate
you know vulnerabilities and bugs from
code before production but the reality
is your code is always going to have
bugs there's always gonna be bugs that
exist in production and vulnerabilities
there and so really thinking about okay
how do we get visibility over what goes
on there and whether that's an attacker
attacking the you know the front facing
part of the application or getting
through to the data store like you
mentioned and thinking about how do we
have coverage over that you know what
you want to be thinking about there is
if I'm if I'm a developer I want to know
if my application ever just responded
with a you know 3 megabyte response size
to something that looked like a sequel
injection because that's somebody
probably doing a select star out of the
users table and so really getting that
sort of visibility at not just the front
facing of the application but really you
know where the data actually lives I'd
say is is a real key to it absolutely
but isn't that more of a DevOps concern
I think what what I'm really seeing with
organizations that are going through the
shift to DevOps to cloud to agile is
that the lines are very much blurring
between that where it used to very much
be okay that was the SIS ops group were
worried about it or that was a security
group or the development group are
worried about this
what I'm seeing the most successful
organizations really come away with as a
pattern is blurring the lines between
those I think it's why though why DevOps
really took off was you know blurring
the lines between developers and
operations allowed the organizations to
move quicker and from a you know
whatever you want to call it as second
DevOps or a dev sec ops or whatever term
we're using today there I think what
really what the organizations that are
doing that successfully are really
finding is that you need to kind of
provide that visibility in a way where
it's not just one group can use it where
it's the development teams where the dev
ops teams the security teams all have
the context they need so that anyone
there can look at something or get an
alert that says hey yeah three Meg's
just went out the door from what looks
like a sequel injection you know that
shouldn't fall to just one team the only
way we scale is to really bring it
across teams and really learn those same
lessons of DevOps I think it's very
comparable actually to kind of the rise
of app dynamics or New Relic or any of
those performance you know application
performance monitoring and the APM tools
is that they didn't build tools that
were just usable by very dedicated
performance experts they brought that
visibility across the full DevOps team
the full development teams and even some
of the security teams and so it's really
learning those same lessons of providing
that visibility in a way where it's it's
very cliche to say but I'll say it
anyway of kind of breaking down the
silos between the teams they're you're
one of my thoughts around that is that
as software engineers we should be
considering that our data store was
already compromised so so with that
thought now we should be making sure
that our secrets within the database are
actually are well encrypted with decent
Kate Eve's our key derivation functions
yeah definitely right I think the the
classic blog post on that of just used
bcrypt
right and you know what what you know
what encryption should I use for my user
passwords anything that it just all
comes back to just use bcrypt absolutely
I think thinking about thinking about
storing the secrets that you store in a
way that either makes it really
difficult for attackers to get to even
exactly as you said even assuming
certain levels of
- or additionally - not just or but also
storing secrets in a way that even when
attackers do get them that they're not
readily recoverable so I'd say the two
examples of that would be no using
putting certain keys inside HSM so even
when you do have some degree of
compromise they don't actually get
access to the raw private key or
something like that and from the other
side like I was joking about with bcrypt
or anything there right you don't want
to be storing your user credentials in
as an md5 hash or something like that
you want to be thinking about okay what
are the you know what it how can I be
using bcrypt or some sort of modern
appropriate way of hashing or encrypting
secrets let's define some depth right so
when an attack it can get through one
obstacle then I've got a whole lot of
other obstacles that have either I've
still got to work their way through yeah
that's exactly it distributed
authentication authorization in session
management is becoming complex what
advice do you have for juicing this
complexity and improving the security
yeah I think the one upside of kind of
one of a few actually upsides of the
kind of descent why well the the
federated identification and everything
like that and kind of you know sam'l and
single sign-on and everything like that
I'm applied to the application layer is
it really does help with the credential
lifecycle management and the kind of
identity and access management and
everything there when you have 50
different apps and they all natively do
their own authentication and everything
like that you can you can do things
right with the individual apps but the
problem is that now you have 50
different data stores of sensitive info
and you're not really sure where
everything lives and everything like
that so as I've been seeing you know the
kind of rise of micro services and API
is everything that rely on a central
authentication scheme that they don't
even handle themselves I think the real
upside is that there is kind of less
surface to defend there and it hopefully
gives us a more understood model of how
do we onboard and off-board users how do
we role credentials when we need to kind
of back that full lifecycle management
of credentials so I definitely think
kind of centralizing some of that there
can be it can be different than what you
were used to at first but it can
actually all
some really strong security benefits yes
so there's quite a few complex these up
front to work through but once you've
actually worked through those then you
get the benefits across your entire
suite right definitely yeah if you're
you know if you're thinking about in 18
months we're gonna have five hundred
different api's or micro services that
we all want to talk together and they
each need to manage their own
authentication it's it's pretty quick to
see how you know how fast that does not
scale and how fast that falls over so I
think there's definitely complexity
upfront of building exactly as you said
building those services right up front
in terms of kind of a centralized
authentication but I think it can really
pay dividends over time as you scale
yeah I just want to talk a little bit
organizational culture and many
organizations we're deploying code
continually how do we make sure that
security is not just a checkbox and that
it's part of the development process in
the software engineers mindset
yeah I think having having tried lots of
different things there that have failed
spectacularly and learning a lot of
lessons along the way and finding a few
that really that did over time work very
well I think the starting point you know
if you're a security professional or a
CIO or CTO going through that shift the
number one lesson that I really learned
was you have to start from exactly as
you said in the beginning the cultural
perspective it's not actually a
technical problem at first it's showing
up from a security perspective insane
look let's be honest here security tools
in the past have really been about in a
lot of ways slowing things down and
trying to have control and everything
around slowing things down and assuring
everything was perfect before I went to
production and everything like that and
the reality is is we're going to agile
and DevOps and see icd things are gonna
go out the door very quickly and the
reality is a lot of times what we
thought of as a security control before
isn't gonna happen until something's
actually already in production so I
think the first most successful piece is
really saying look the way that we've
done security needs to change and we're
gonna try some new approaches as part of
this and you know there's gonna be a
couple things that won't work and
there's gonna be some things that do but
I'd say the single most important bit is
upfront how we engage the development
teams and DevOps teams with security is
by being honest right up front and
saying look if we try to keep doing
secure
the way that we've done it it's not
gonna work it's not gonna scale and we
want to be open and honest with you
about that because we want to really
bring effective security approaches to
the table and we need your help to do
that
the only way in which we really go on
this kind of journey to DevOps and cloud
together securely is by working together
on it and so what we will provide from
the security perspective is really
working on new approaches that help you
out that you can consume our ask at the
same time is that you let us know what
works and what doesn't and that we work
together on this collaboratively because
again if we just keep trying to do
security the way we've done it for 20
years
it just gets routed around in the shift
to DevOps and cloud if it can't keep up
we had a show with Francis Reynard on TV
I cops
Francis reynard's the guy that started
up deep-set con yes yeah he's awesome
yeah yeah so there was show 288 we
touched on how the rapid rate of change
actually means we can make things more
secure how do you see this working with
continuous deployment yeah so this was
something that if you would ask me on my
first day as a as I see so you know
would this shift make us more secure I
would have started laughing and then
running for a because there is in my
mind it just it would have seemed like
it would be an absolute disaster what I
really learned going through that shift
is believe it or not it actually can
make you more secure and the reason is
that we kind of have this this new
playing field to try new approaches and
the biggest thing that I really learned
out of it is that no matter what your
development methodology or your DevOps
methodology or you know deployment or
anything is you're always going to have
vulnerabilities you're always gonna have
issues that you need to react to and the
problem with the kind of slower older
models of like a waterfall or something
like that is you don't really have the
ability to react if you've ever tried if
you've ever worked in a place that does
waterfall development and you've tried
to rush an emergency patch out the door
you know what an utter nightmare it
actually is and so this was really when
I this is really how I learned the
lesson is that as you go to DevOps as
you go to see ICD and everything there
it's not that magically vulnerabilities
go away we're always gonna have
vulnerabilities it's that for the first
time you can react because instead of
reading
that emergency fix out the door that's a
total you know nightmare to get all
these political teams to buy in and
everything like that now it's just
another deploy and if you're in an
environment it's the point every day or
every week or anything like that it's
not it's not that scary to just make
another deploy because you already
organizationally know how to do it if
you only deploy over 18 months and
suddenly you need to deploy six weeks
after something is found
it's a nightmare and so this is why I
really actually agree with what he said
which is that if we seize this
opportunity and do it right and change
the way we've done security it can
actually be a net positive for security
yeah well we get a lot better at
deploying right exactly and yeah and the
other thing is it gives us a whole lot
more opportunities to inspect and adapt
yeah that's exactly it so how does the
culture of the organization that has
security is part of their development
process look and how would you go about
achieving this in organizations in teams
where security is seen as a blocker yeah
I think so much of it is really
acknowledging that right up front and
saying look I I recognize that security
has been a blocker you know as we're
going through this shift to be a DevOps
or cloud or whatever the shift is really
recognizing that Security's been a
blocker and saying sometimes just as X
as explicitly as saying that I recognize
Security's been a blocker we need to
find new ways of doing it and empowering
the teams to be security self-sufficient
as we're going through this shift that's
why that's why I'm actually so hopeful
about the shift to DevOps and cloud is
it kind of gives us this clean slate to
try new approaches and saying look
Security's been a blocker in the past
we've recognized that that's just kind
of a hat it came out of the whole sort
of waterfall model and everything there
the way in which we build and deliver
applications has changed care needs to
change as well and I think the first
thing a successful security team needs
to really do is say that up front and
say look we recognize we need to change
we're gonna be working on that you know
a lot of times we want to hear from you
what is the best way that you could
really interact with security is that us
embedding somebody in your team is it
training someone from your team kind of
like we talked about and earlier on it
could be you know what tools would give
you visibility or anything like that how
we provide it but it really security in
a lot of ways almost shifts to becoming
an internal Consulting Group that really
it needs to make its customers which are
the development teams and DevOps team's
happy it can't just show up and say no
because what's what I've actually seen
there is that the security teams that
don't adapt it's not like the business
stops operating the development teams
and DevOps teams just stopped speaking
to security it's really only right it's
crazy it's I think security teams are at
this inflection point that like IT
procurement teams were eight years ago
at the start of cloud where they said oh
yeah anytime you want a server it's
gonna take us 12 months to procure one
and so the development Eames said great
we just put down a credit card we spun
up eight different instances and we
don't need to speak to you anymore
Security's at that same inflection if
they keep you in a blocker they just
they're gonna get routed around so I
have worked for quite a few
organizations in New Zealand I'm
wondering whether this is a New Zealand
specific thing or not I'm not sure but
how would you go about changing the
culture of an organization where the
development team is just not interested
in security and developers do take the
direction of the organization sure yeah
and I don't think that's necessarily
just a New Zealand thing I think
certainly over my career I've seen
plenty of organizations where that has
been true and I would say that you know
it may sound wildly optimistic which
security people are not usually accused
of being but I really think that that's
actually improving over time that it's
really something that I've certainly
seen in my career change over time
really regardless of locale you know
some locales move at different speeds
and others or change at different times
but I've really on the whole seen that
start to shift so I'd say that's the
good news of up front
I'd say specifically how you try to
shift organizations or how I've seen
organizations like that shift in the
past it's a lot of times in its kind of
going back to some of the things I've I
sound like a broken record on but it's
providing them with security tools that
they can use themselves directly I mean
putting yourself in the developers shoes
where they're very antagonistic is
antagonistic to security I think a lot
of times it's because the only security
product or anything that they've used
spat out a hundred thousand page
a report of which 99 thousand pages of
it were false positives and they're like
well this is useless like I'm not I'm
not interested in working with this sort
of thing so really giving them
actionable information and tools that
they can use directly a lot of times
that's the right starting point if
you're showing that look there can be
value for you here in a way that is not
gonna cost you a ton of effort or time
or anything like that and so I think
half of it is kind of cultural like we
we talked about a minute ago of really
coming them and saying we've recognized
things need to change and the other side
is then technical and really saying hey
what data would be useful to you from a
security perspective I recognize that
you don't want to you view your job is
writing new features or writing new
product you don't want to be bogged down
with heavy weight security what would be
kind of light touch security that would
be useful to you and really starting
from there and working with them on that
we've got to make their lives easier
exactly do you have any tips on getting
developers to the point where they
actually enjoy security where it's
something they want to do you know this
sounds so simple and I I couldn't
believe the effectiveness of it which
was when we started at Etsy we really
started investing in visibility and
really starting to say okay we need that
kind of visibility into attacks and
anomalies that are happening across our
applications and our ap eyes and
everything like that what we did at
first is we made kind of dashboards
anything like that and we just used them
themselves or use them ourselves as
security folks we put up some dashboards
in our you know security area of the
headquarters and everything like that
and to your point into your question the
most interesting thing we found is we
had a couple folks walk by and go oh
what's that and and they'd say and we'd
say oh actually if you take a look here
at this data that's somebody attacking
your service right now and what was
fascinating is you'd see these
developers that I had thought you know
maybe at first didn't care about
security or were ambivalent to it or
something like that go wait what
seriously like people are attacking my
service and you know from the security
side we like of course they are I mean
that's just second nature that you
assume that you're under attack all the
time but a lot of times when you when
you speak with folks on the development
side of the DevOps side they think they
need to be explicitly targeted and not
that you know both folks are
attacking all the time they're really
you know they're they're throwing
attacks out there and they're seeing
where they have success and they're
pivoting against those and so our lesson
learned on that was if we brought
visibility to the engineering teams they
really got way more into it than we ever
expected I think you know the a friend
of mine put it really well they're like
yeah you know name an engineer that
doesn't get excited about some new graph
of data that they've never had access to
youth for the first time and I was like
well when you say it like that yeah it
sounds blindingly obvious but it took us
a long time to learn that lesson which
is if we can give them visibility
suddenly it's really really interesting
and that they can start to self-serve
and say oh this is somebody attacking us
over here like we want to maybe those
bugs that we thought were totally
theoretical and we were gonna prioritize
them off and you know q4 of the
following year actually we see somebody
attacking that service today so yeah
well you know what we are gonna bump up
the priority of those here really yeah
making it interactive all 0 is the
easiest and fastest way to implement
authentication and authorization
architectures into your apps and api's
allow your users to login with username
and password social and enterprise
identity providers such as Facebook
Twitter ad or office 365 or without
passwords using slack or whatsapp
getting started is very easy use one of
more than 40 SDKs and add a few lines of
code no credit card required get the
free plan at auth0 dot io / SC radio
that's a uth the number 0 io / SE radio
aussie row is trusted by developers at
Atlassian Mozilla Optimizely in
financial times try it out at our zero
dot io / se radio and get back time
building core features we've got a
section on visibility that we're gonna
shift into shortly you mentioned access
policies in one of your talks are
building a modern security engineering
organization yeah startups basically
don't have them in half important that
is as an organization grows that they
need to implement access policies but
not to remove capabilities from the
engineers you had some good examples on
how you would implement solid access
policies throughout
the organization without removing
capabilities could you share some of
these yeah definitely
and those were very hard to learned
lessons because I screwed it up plenty
of times along the way so I hope
everybody gets to learn from my pain
which is that you know at first the
reaction can tend to be you know whether
it's your a new security person coming
into a new organization or whether
you're a security person or a
development team you know a developer or
a DevOps engineer that suddenly finds
out about a new either new acquisition
that the company made or a new cloud
project that's going on the first
reaction can just be oh we need to shut
down all access immediately while we
figure out what's going on and the
reality is that you know people don't
the engineering organization doesn't
just grab a bunch of access because they
they you know feel like it would be fun
or something like that people tend to
have that because it's how they're
getting their jobs done and so I think
that the first lesson is not just
blindly restricting access or something
like that when something feels unsafe
but rather figuring out what the
capability actually is that you know
different developers or different DevOps
engineers are using and building a safe
way to do it so I'll give you an example
that I think plenty of us have lived
through which is you know development or
DevOps access to production and at first
that seems you know scary that okay SSH
is on every box there and everybody has
keys access everything and everything
like that and so the first reaction is
oh shut everything down the reality is
like okay well why do people ever
actually you know why does a a mid-level
developer on a let's say a front-end
team ever SSH to production that seems
crazy well when you go ask them and talk
to them
more often than not the reason is so
that they can actually get debug logs
right it's oh we got some sort of report
about an issue there were the steps to
reproduce the issue weren't correct or
we're totally missing and so we want to
pull some logs to actually try to figure
out what's going on so we can root cause
this bug and fix it and that's a very
sensible reason right that's part of
their job and so what you kind of build
back from then is okay well they don't
need access to production they need
access to logs and data so they can do
their job and so what you start to think
about that is okay well how do we pull
logs off production
bring them back to a centralized login
host surface those via some sort of tool
whether it's a Splunk or an elk or a
sumo or something like that and do it in
a way where folks can get the data they
need but it's it's controlled and we've
really reduced access so over time
you've been able to kill off that SSH
access and reduce your attack service
but you didn't get rid of the capability
that the engineer needs to do their job
which was view logs and kind of root
cause bugs and so that's really the lens
I'd recommend thinking about it through
is think about what the capability they
actually need it is and don't treat the
symptom which would be access to
production you know treat the underlying
cause that leading up to the show you
mentioned improving phishing in security
awareness training it's a common
understanding that trying to teach
people not to click phishing links
doesn't work how do you go about making
a security awareness stick in the minds
of everyone involved in the development
and ops process yeah I'd say there are
kind of two sides of security training
there's there's the general like
security awareness and the phishing and
and all of that and that's where I I'd
say the biggest shift that we need to go
through and the biggest lesson learned I
had was you're not trying to train
people down to where no one's ever gonna
click link because the reality is that's
never gonna happen right you're never
gonna be able to drop that number to
zero of people who click on potentially
dodgy links what you can train up and
raise over time is the number of people
who report when they get something like
that to security whether it's they just
saw it and it looked fishy to them and
so they want to report it or even they
clicked on it and then I said you know
actually that seemed a bit strange let
me let me tell someone there and mate
you know and you really want to you
really want to reinforce that they're
not gonna get in trouble that they're
really gonna get rewarded for reporting
things like that because all you need is
one person to report it before so you
can start you're kind of dfi are and
security operations process or you know
incident triage or anything like that
and so you really want to raise the
number of people that report those at
the same time of course you want to try
to train people don't click on stuff
less but the reality is that number is
never gonna go to zero so I'd say that's
one side of the house which is the kind
of phishing trainee and everything there
the other side of security awareness
training is for the developers right
developers DevOps teams and training
about secure code creation or delivery
or anything like that and again I think
the way that we've done training they're
just like with the fishing training can
actually be kind of turned on its head
which is in the past we've really tried
to do the training to get people to
write perfect code basically which is oh
here's a here's an anti-pattern you know
never do this always do this instead or
always do that instead and the problem
is everyone sits through those trainings
they're usually all day long they are
tremendously boring and I say that even
as a security professional and everybody
walks out of there bored and not
remembering it and just saying like men
I should never talk to the security team
because they are incredibly boring what
we actually want to focus on there and
what I found successful is the metric
you want to be tracking out of your
security training for the development
side of things is how many people engage
with security how many people and how
frequently people engage with security
afterwards I don't expect developers to
walk out of security like a modern
security training and say I now know how
to write perfect code what you want them
to walk out of there with is hey these
seemed like areas that were things that
the security team had done some sort of
training around I'm gonna go ask them
for their input on this as I'm designing
it or as I'm writing it or as I'm you
know implementing it or anything they're
really kind of just like the the fishing
side of things which is you want to be
driving engagement out of that you want
people to reach out say this link was
fishy or you want people to reach out
say hey I'm gonna be collecting this new
form of user data
how should I protect it I was thinking
hashing but I don't know is that the
right use here and that's really the
thing to be tracking and the way I found
it the most effective to actually do
that a lot of times of folks is for that
training the less theoretical the better
and so what I found there is a lot of
times even just rolling back issues that
I've got voter real vulnerabilities that
have happened in a particular code base
that the organization owns so maybe a
mobile app or a web app or something
like that and roll them back and teach
the developers off of those there was
real issues that have actually happened
to the organization in the past yeah the
way I say that is it's like trying to
teach the sea levels how to code and
they just you know they're not going to
get
so don't do it so just build
relationships with them instead so that
we have issues they come to you and ask
for your expertise right that's exactly
it yeah I've got a question on Fleet
modelling now that I basically sprung up
with with my discussion with Huronia
mm-hmm in my discussion with phonon the
network security show her and mentioned
that our penetration testing hasn't been
that effective in creating attack
resistant systems and that a very
effective threat modeling technique was
to have a read team or I'm attacking
team a member is part of your
development team and work out the
possible ways of breaking into whatever
it is that you're working on but then to
have the blue team which is the
defending team or the development team
our members question the weed team
individual how would we notice this
thing happening you then design your
monitoring and alerting around what
would have caught the suit occur I've
noticed a similar theme in your attack
driven defense talk in terms of
applications security what would you add
to this threat modeling process yeah so
first of all I've just kind of a side
note there I I completely agree with
that methodology I mean I think Haroon
is one of the smartest people in
security he's absolutely fantastic and
so totally agree with that methodology
what I found successful there is you
know not it's if something you you
mentioned briefly in that which is not
just oh how did you find a particular
issue or anything like that but asking
yourself as a development team or DevOps
team the hard question which is how
would we have known how would we have
detected this how would we have if we
did detect it how would we have known
that somebody else hasn't exploited it
six months previously or that this
attacker didn't find something else
there and I think this really goes to
the heart of the penetration testing
question that you said which is that the
problem from for most organizations is
that pen testing isn't really pen
testing pen testing is kind of I'd say
better described at this point as
vulnerability and numeration right you
get this big report at the end that says
here's a stack of vulnerabilities and
you go fix them or you go upgrade or you
go patch or something like that the
problem is that that big stack of
vulnerabilities is not how an attacker
actually attacks real systems and I say
this as a former and you know recovering
pen tester myself which is that that big
stack of alms often it's
okay the criticals and the highs are
what everybody focuses on and then you
ignore the mediums and the lows the
reality as an actual attacker is often
it's a series of lows or mediums that
you chained together that make for the
really effective attacks of how you
actually compromise an organization so
I'd say there's kind of there's a couple
things here one is running those more
realistic Red Team simulations which is
not just discover a bug report that bug
and kind of operate in isolation but
rather try to actually get at real data
and for the blue team side of things
whether that's a security team or
development team or DevOps teams
asking yourselves how would we detect
this how would we make this harder for
the attacker how would we get the
visibility that they had just discovered
a real bug or that they started
exploiting it there or that they'd
actually done all of that without us
detecting and now they're exfiltrating
data and maybe we detect at that point
or anything like that and so I think
people are starting to that from the
kind of endpoint and infrastructure side
and where I see the more modern
organizations going right now is
recognizing that the application level
is kind of the next big piece to tackle
there I'm so I'm just gonna move into a
into a section around visibility near
mmm-hmm what are some of the risks of
lack of visibility insufficient logging
and monitoring yeah it's it's exactly
what we actually just went through on
the the previous question in a lot of
ways of the the risks there that you
don't know right I forget the stat so I
would probably completely mess it up but
from the Verizon data breach report the
percentage of organizations that are
told to by a third party they've been
breached is staggeringly high I think it
was the number one way in which
organizations find out is that they
never even detected they get told by
somebody else that they've been breached
and so that's the cost of not thinking
about this from the vulnerability or
from the visibility perspective is that
you get breached and you don't even have
a chance to react or to try to cut off
the attacker halfway or ideally prevent
the attacker from getting that data at
all in the first place you know the
organization gets told that the IP
address is sending attacks right exactly
right you get a call from Brian Krebs or
The Wall Street Journal asking for
comment on why your data is up on this
thing and that's that's not it
active security program yes so how do we
build logging and instrumentation into
our applications to capture our security
defects and attacker activity yeah I
think that the first point is and this
is a really nuanced and deep topic right
there that we could we could spend hours
on just by itself so I'd say the
starting point is you start with what
you have you know every organization has
some logs or something like that you
know just like when we're talking about
taking away access but not capabilities
this is really where you get to for one
out of that you reduce that access of in
that example SSH access to production
but at the same time it really sets the
groundwork now for the visibility side
of things which is ok if we have our
logs in one place now we can start to
build kind of visibility on top of those
now the challenge that you run into real
quick there is that the logs are never
as complete as you want them to be a lot
of stuff never even makes it to the logs
like if you're dealing with you know
your web applications and your API is
you know a lot of data about your gits
your HTTP gets gets logged but your HTTP
posts where all the data is actually in
the post body that doesn't make analogs
because you don't want a long sensitive
data like that so you you recognize some
of the walls that you run into real
quick but the starting point is
absolutely your logs and then you start
to recognize the value from it and you
start to move up and say ok how do we
get deeper visibility into the actual
application or anything now the details
of exactly how you do it obviously vary
by organization and technology and
everything like that
but the methodology is really the same
across all organizations which is you
start from logs you recognize that that
gives a good starting point for
visibility and then you recognize hey we
need deeper visibility into where the
application logic actually lives and at
the same time we need the ability to
react because logs are inherently
reactive and you ultimately want to be
able to be proactive all this sort of
stuff and and block attackers and stop
attacks that we also need correlation
between the different logs as well exact
as attackers are moving across the
systems right totally agree I want to
discuss I'm monitoring in statistics
graphing for application security of
Kevin's stats d click D cabin in
graphite is one solution in my book
series there's a previous director of us
Aditi can you explain what the sort of
setup gives us and how we capture
security defects in malicious events
using it yeah so I think the the running
joke at Etsy was always if it moves
graphs graph it and if it doesn't move
graph it just in case it decides to make
a move for it and so the the challenge
the the first thing is just kind of
getting that sort of data
right getting the graph data getting the
logging data and everything like that
what you click quickly realize out of
that is now you're drowning in data and
so what really what you start to think
about that is okay what are the most
actionable things I can start to surface
up what are no anomalies across my
application requests or the the
responses that my application is sending
or anything like that they're gonna be
useful not only from a reliability
perspective and a performance
perspective but also from a security
perspective and then from a security
perspective let's start to correlate
that with attacks right let's get some
graphs around when people are attempting
sequel injection or cross-site scripting
or anything like that and let's start to
correlate those because you know just
because there's a spike in sequel
injection that's probably just another
day on the internet what you actually
want to know is is somebody are we
seeing spikes and attacks that are also
triggering anomalies in our applications
and indicating that they're discovering
real bugs now whether they're
exploitable or not so you start to build
off of the the base that you build off
of is getting that sort of data at all
then you start to build more and more
actionable data on top of it and that's
gonna be a little bit different for
every organization but the overall
methodology there that I kind described
is really the same for everybody
can you explain here we capture high
fidelity information without the false
positives and missing events we should
be catching oh yeah that is a very good
question that is something that is a
challenge for almost every organization
I mean the funny thing in the caveat
here and the full disclosure is this is
why we actually left Etsy and built
signal Sciences which is a product that
actually does all this for you they can
just drop in to get that sort of
coverage I'm not here to be a vendor
shill nobody nobody needs to hear more
about vendors myself included but this
is a really challenging problem
we spent a ton of time building out
in-house at Etsy and trying and failing
and trying and failing and finally
having some real success with um and
that's the reason we actually spun out a
whole a whole company and with a product
around this the big thing I would say
for everybody there is getting away from
the kind of classic legacy signature
based approaches of if you you know the
you look at the only things that have
ever existed in the space and if things
like legacy laughs like web app
firewalls and the problem is they're
just you know big piles of signatures
and reg X's in a box and the problem was
everyone who's worked with real
production applications before knows how
weird they are knows how production
traffic is much stranger than you would
think before you've worked with it and
so the amount of false positives that
those sort of things trigger all the
time is staggering and so I think
getting away from that sort of approach
and really starting to think what are
practical anomalies that exist
regardless of the scale of the
applications that's really the good
starting point and then it gets a lot
more complex from there her and Mia
mentioned in the network security show
that IDS's intrusion detection systems
demo well but largely don't work that
well and enterprises basically for what
you're just saying yeah when the
representative gives a demo I'm on the
IDS it detects the attack but most real
attacks just looked like normal user
traffic so IDs is in most cases are not
catching the reality X it looks like the
EC trip yarn host intrusion detection
system attempted to address these
concerns here well did this work and
what advances have there been since you
presented this talk in 2013 yeah so
completely agree with IDs is there as
Haroon was saying he's spot-on
and I'd say exactly even worse than that
it's that you lose both ways it's that
they demo well but that's not how people
attack systems but then at the same time
when you put them in production those
signatures tend to match on a whole
bunch of things that are completely
legitimate traffic so you lose with
false positives and you lose with false
negatives and I think that's been
completely the case with both kind of
legacy IDS's and legacy laughs there as
well the web app firewalls so that the
the IDs side of things yeah that really
led to the
creation of trip yarn which was based
off of an awesome talk out of Facebook
that they had built something kind of
hungry around that and then Etsy built
trip yarn what funny is what became trip
yarn or what trip yarn has become today
is actually a West query so if you've
heard of a West query that's that's come
out of Facebook that was actually
initially a joint open source release
called Midas between Etsy and Facebook
which was built off of trip yarns so it
all kind of goes back to the same thing
so OS query is kind of the modern one
today there and yeah there were a bunch
of good lessons learned around that I
think really aiming for on the host
intrusion detection side of things it
goes back to I think one of the first
points of the conversation the first
question that you asked which is Rob how
attacks are changing and it used to be
very that kind of network and
infrastructure driven attack where you'd
put a IDs out there off of a span port
or something like that and now how do
people attack organisations they attack
the web applications and they attack the
endpoints and so shifting to covering
the endpoints there with kind of a
modern approach to a host intrusion
detection and really looking for
attacker activities and not for some
sort of signature is exactly how you go
about it and really it's the same
philosophy at the the web application
side of things it's not just looking for
a signature for sequel injection but
looking for how do people abuse the
business logic of the application to get
the data that they want via what seemed
like legitimate functionality you
mentioned in your attack driven defense
talk they didn't practice sophisticated
persistence mechanisms okay Mel whether
I want to persist or sit up shot I won't
be detected rather aim to detect the
basics can you elaborate on that some
more yeah definitely
I I think that the you know often time
are oftentimes our industry gets so
focused on like the shiniest object the
coolest is zero day you know the most
advanced persistent mechanism and so you
start thinking about you know okay well
will this did you know will my new
approach to tech that and like no it
won't well then it stands worthless the
reality is that the perfect is very much
the enemy of the good
Alex almost puts this really well he
talked about in his keynote at blackhat
this year of security nihilism right I'm
saying that oh and the
one edge case it won't be perfect so I
shouldn't do anything at all
the reality has actual practical
defenders is the opposite it's that you
want to make your adversaries have to do
the most advanced possible things
because that's incredibly expensive and
that's incredibly complex and the the
reality is that they're probably gonna
mess something up along the way that you
detect and so you want to be thinking
about how can I make sure that yeah I
detect the most low-hanging fruit of
persistence mechanisms then in a lateral
movement and things like that then how
can I detect the semi advance and then
the advanced and if I have to make my
attackers you know have to use the most
amazing persistence mechanisms great
I've really won because I have shifted
the set of attackers that can
successfully attack me down to such a
small set of people made it so expensive
that that's really the the best possible
outcome I can I can go for right it's
not the advanced 0 days and amazing
persistence mechanisms that are owning
everybody up today it's the
off-the-shelf stuff um it's the land
beyond the end point and just moving
vehicles that you found from there
because 2-factor office Intan abled and
there's nothing there's no hid sitting
on the laptop it's the web application
that nobody has visibility into and
there was no rate limiting and now the
totally legitimate interface for
querying an ID
somebody just scripted that up and did
10 million of them before anybody even
noticed and so it's it's sort of
practical things of how we actually get
compromised that we need visibility in
place for and to force our attackers to
actually be more advanced you mentioned
in one of your talks are building a
modern security engineering organization
that the cost of a tech is significantly
dropped do you have any statistics on
there and can you explain what you mean
by it totally because that's that's one
of those where the reality is more
nuanced than that but when you've got to
distill it down into one bullet point on
a slide I think some of the nuance can
not very much get lost
I'd say you know there were there are a
bunch of different groups of attackers
you know you're you see them oftentimes
bucket is state level or hacktivist or
IP focused or you know whatever the
reality I'd say is the cost of attack
for a lot of groups can be very
expensive but in general if you look at
if you are just somebody that is you
know has general kind of
engineering literacy and you wanted to
go download a tool and download a
tutorial to attack systems and you try
to do that 20 years ago the tools were
less available the techniques were less
published on or you really had to go
searching for them or know somebody or
learn from peers or anything there you
look at kind of modern tools and
techniques and what's available and
they've really proliferated you're right
there's a there's a bunch of different
you know kind of step-by-step guides on
how you attack something in a nice GUI
tool to go do it for you and everything
like that and so I think for vast
swathes of attackers and a bunch of
different attack groups cost of attack
has very much gotten cheaper because you
just launch you know automated tools
against everything and then you pivot to
the ones that you're actually seeing
success with and so you don't have to go
hyper target one organization and really
try and fail and try and fail and try
and fail and eventually get in you just
launch attacks on everybody and you go
you go focus on the ones where you're
actually seeing success and so I think
for those groups of attackers costume
attack has really significantly dropped
I think for other groups of attackers
and I think it was a fill Venables it
was a seesaw of goldman said this really
well which was you know attackers have
bosses and budgets too and I think it's
absolutely true for a lot of different
groups of attackers there so you want to
make things not economical for them and
that kind of goes back to our previous
point is make them have to use the most
advanced thing don't stress over the
fact that the most advanced thing might
work it's that it's you should be
rejoicing because everything else you
did made everything that was cheaper not
work for the attacker how do you got
about increasing the cost for the
attackers what are some ideas yeah so I
think that what we're really seeing is
this fundamental shift in security
approaches of the last 20 years has
really been focused on this idea of
prevention right put the put the magic
box out there and it will stop the
breach by the antivirus and it will stop
the breach or something like that what
we're really shifting to and what I
think is the fundamentally just more
effective approaches the notion of
detection and visibility right it's not
deploy the magic box that will stop it
you'll never know anything about it it's
get the visibility so you can detect
an attacker as early as possible in the
attack chain and detect them when
they're doing recon or when they first
gained a toehold via a application or an
endpoint or something there because
that's how you can really iterate and
start to increase cost for them if they
only get a toehold in before you detect
them and you're able to reimagine at
machine or patch that application that
means it's really expensive for them
because they didn't make it they didn't
just bypass a prevention mechanism and
then no one even knew they were there
and they were able to move through the
rest of the attack chain it's you want
to make the attackers scared that
they're going to be detected at every
level and so they have to operate really
cautiously or anything like that and
then you detect them via a different way
right it's the focus on that visibility
and detection so that you can shut them
down as early as possible in the attack
chain and now they need a hundred
attempts to do something where they just
did an evasion of your prevention
mechanism before and they only needed
one attempt to get by that and so those
100 types are gonna be way more
expensive than that woman so what about
bug bounties Ametek simulations and
penetration testing do you want to just
explain for the listeners what bug
bounties are and how effective you think
they are and also Tech simulations yeah
so I absolutely love them so I would say
bug bounty is so bug bounties for those
who aren't familiar with them are
essentially a a program where you can
say as defenders hey security
researchers um if you look for these
type of issues and you look for them on
these specifically scoped systems or
applications or anything there and you
play by these rules then if you report
those issues to us we will reward you in
some way that might be monetary rewards
it might even just be a teacher or it
might even just be putting their name up
on a hall-of-fame of people who found
issues or something like that
and the reason why it sounds so
straightforward but the reason why these
programs exist historically is that if
you were a security researcher and you
found a vulnerability in some sort of
company in their applications or their
infrastructure and you reported it to
them you had probably a 50/50 chance of
getting sued it was really scary to
report those issues even if you were
very well-meaning and so bug bounties
are really cool because they can let
everybody kind of act in good faith we
can say hey researchers if you behave in
this way and play
these rules we're going to reward you
and researchers if they go play by these
rules can go get rewarded for things and
you know really work on their techniques
and you know cool ways of finding new
bugs and everything like that so it
really is a win-win for folks if done
right why I really like them having been
on all sides of them now in my career is
that they I think are in general they're
very good at the things that pen tests
are kind of weak at and pen tests are
very good at the things that bug
bounties are weaken and the reason for
that is that bug bounties can I'd say in
the general case they can give you
really good broad but kind of shallow
coverage they can test a lot of
different a lotta different attack
service but they're not actually going
that deep on it um whereas pen tests
whatever we've all kind of done pen
tests the problem is you typically get a
few pen testers for a few weeks and
you're always stuck with this really bad
choice which is do I ask them to try to
cover a ton of stuff and I know that
they won't go that deep on it or do I
ask them to focus on just a couple areas
and they'll go really deep on that but
they won't cover really anything else
and so the to really augment each other
because now you can use your pen test
for very focused things let's I want you
to go very focus on this particular API
or something like that and then you can
use your bug bounties for that broad
coverage and then how they all kind of
chained together into a really effective
attack simulation is that you can use
all of these as a feedback loop into the
way that you're thinking about
visibility so what you start to think
about is okay this bug bounty
participant or this pen tester found
this bug how would we have detected that
and how would we know that they didn't
discover ten other things that they're
not reporting to us or how do we know
that somebody six months earlier found
the same thing has been exploiting it
for six months before this person
actually found it and the answer is when
you ask yourself those questions at
first you're gonna be really unhappy
with your answers because for most
organizations that are that have not
started going through the shift yet you
don't really have an answer and so that
immediately guides how you start to
think about visibility and getting that
sort of coverage hmm and it's not I'm
another good reason why you get the red
teamer into the development team right
exactly
yep you want that feedback loop right
be like if we deployed an application to
production and then we said oh that's it
we don't need to monitor its performance
or its reliability or anything like that
I'm sure it's fine that's kind of where
we're at with security right we've got
these applications in production but you
need that visibility and so when there
is an issue you can detect it you can
react it's just like with performance
you know if suddenly all of your
production web server CPU spikes you
want to know about that before somebody
calling you saying that I can't use your
site because it's down well interesting
personal project so Venus do you have
on-the-go account design yeah so I'd say
the blessing and the curse of starting a
security company is that it is the vast
majority of your time but I'd say so
it's personal projects and work projects
definitely overlap the vast majority at
this point but I'd say the most exciting
one for me there has been really focused
on getting people coverage across this
broader spectrum of threats that they
actually face at the web layer right
getting giving people coverage through
sequel I and XSS and all that sure
that's important and you know we do that
everything like that but I think what's
been most rewarding to me is getting
people that coverage over the business
logic and the application misuse and the
application DDoS and everything there
and getting people that sort of
visibility so for me on the personal
project side it's just kind of
continuously feeding back into the
product around effective ways of giving
people that sort of coverage what if we
not discussed that we really should have
in the show man Ida good question and
also I think we've covered a bunch of
great stuff I mean I think that the I
think you really nailed it with a bunch
of the questions and a bunch of your
points around you know this shift to
DevOps and cloud it feels scary it feels
like it's gonna make things worse the
reality is it can actually make things
better at the same time bringing these
kind of effective security controls in a
new way is really what helps enable the
development teams and the DevOps teams
especially those that have historically
not been interested in talking to
security because it's been so
heavyweight there's been such a blocker
and then really thinking about that all
through the terms of attack simulations
and effective read teams and thinking
about that as a feedback
into visibility that you can use to
empower the rest of the organization I
mean those are far in a way those themes
are what I see across all of these kind
of leading enterprises that are handling
the shift really well we can people find
out more about you and what you do
simple science is calm I'm on Twitter as
well at same Lackey because I am NOT not
creative at naming a Twitter handle
there and honestly if you're going
through any of this sort of shift I
think we're all we're all facing the
same challenges and so something that's
really rewarding to me is I love having
conversations with folks that are going
through the shift and just sharing
lessons learned with each other on it
because at the end of the day we're all
fighting the same battles on this and
the more that we can help each other the
better so I actually have opened EMS on
Twitter my email saying at signal
Sciences if if you're going through any
of this and you just kind of want to
chat with a peer who's gone through it
and you want to avoid some of their pain
I'm more than happy to share with you a
bunch of the stuff that we didn't get to
deep dive as much in here or anything
like that so however I can be helpful
please just give me a shout oh throw
some links on the show notes around
there as well do you have any other
recent podcasts or conference talks that
you think would help our listeners
understand what aspects of application
security we should be focusing on yeah I
did a talk at blackhat a couple months
ago on the way in which to adapt the
kind of individual pieces of the sdlc so
how do you change static analysis how do
you change dynamic scanning how do you
think about visibility and everything
like that that it might be worth while
the folks here I think they posted
videos now if not you can just email me
and I'll send you the full deck and
everything like that and that's been
that's been the the main one I'd say
recently and then I'm hopefully working
on some some new material for a full a
few different talks next year one of
which I'm actually hoping I'll be
presenting you mentioned francois at dev
sec on in singapore in february so
hopefully all i'll be out in that area
and if he wants cool cool
are you saying thanks for joining us
today hey thanks so much for having me
on really enjoyed the conversation this
was super fun
thanks thanks again for software
engineering radio this was Kim Cadiz
thanks for listening to se Radio an
educational program brought to you by
Triple E software magazine for more
about the podcast including other
episodes visit our website at SE - radio
net to provide feedback you can comment
on each episode on the website or reach
us on LinkedIn Facebook Twitter or
through our slack channel at SC
radio.com you can also email us at team
@ SC - radio net this and all other
episodes of SU radio is licensed under
Creative Commons license 2.5 thanks for
listening